## Sulabh Shrestha

## Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Engineer

Certified Azure Data Engineer with 3+ years of cloud computing and machine learning experience. Proficient in cloud services to migrate, wrangle and process big data using data orchestration tools. Successfully developed and completed the car damage project at Mpercept Technology and currently working on MotionsCloud as a Cloud DevOps Engineer.

#### $\sim$

sulabhshrestha@outlook.com



+977-9808640452



Kathmandu, Nepal



sulabhshrestha.com/

#### in

linkedin.com/in/sulabhshrestha



github.com/codexponent

#### M

sulabh4.medium.com

## **SKILLS**

Cloud Computing: Azure,

Big Data: Synapse Analytics, Redshift

Data Engineering: Data Factory, Data Pipelines

DevOps Tools: GitHub Actions, Azure DevOps

Programming Languages: Python, Java

Databases: SQL, MySQL, Postgresql, CosmosDB

Version Control System: Git

IaC: Terraform, Ansible

Orchestration: Docker, Kubernetes

#### **LANGUAGES**

#### English

Full Professional Proficiency

#### Hindi

Professional Working Proficiency

#### Nepali

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Cloud DevOps/Data Engineer MotionsCloud

06/2019 - Present Kathmandu, Nepal

Munich based AI startup company in Germany but working from Nepal as Work from Home (WFH)

#### Tacks

- Migrated Amazon S3 datasets into Azure File Shares for all the VM's to share the dataset without downloading for each VM which saved 100's of GB on cloud storage.
- Dockerize their entire ML deployment code with automation and scheduling enabled which saved 10% of the employee time to turn it on/off manually every day.
- Implemented Azure DevOps into the organization with builds, releases and automation building better quality deployments and securing connection strings.
- Monitoring, Automating, and Scheduling whole Training GPU instances with notification enabled saving nearly 30% costs on unused GPU training time.
- Configured Azure Kubernetes Service to scale the ML deployment from one to 100's customers at once.
- Designed a Fault tolerance, backup enabled system for our ML deployment to have zero downtime.

Contact: Lex Tan (CEO) - lex@motionscloud.com

# **Artificial Intelligence Developer** MPercept Technology

06/2018 - 05/2019 Kathmandu, Nepal

Task

- Employed Python as the programming language, Scalable as the annotation tool and OpenCV as the library to write utility functions which includes image masker scripts to mask images and converter scripts to convert our data format into COCO dataset schema.
- Harnessed Python parallel and concurrent processing features to download, mask and augment the images respectively which saved 50% of the image processing time.
- Changed EC2 instance from one GPU to eight GPU which enabled multi training on the same instance and saved the training time as nearly as four times by giving two gpus for each training task.
- Implemented Genetic Algorithm Shuffled Frog Leaping Algorithm(GA-SFLA) from scratch in Python for NEWS clustering task.

Contact: Khuong Duy Vu (CTO) - pablo@motionscloud.com

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Engineer Associate (01/2021 - 01/2023)

Azure Data Engineers integrate, transform, and consolidate data from various data systems that are suitable for building analytics solutions.

## **EDUCATION**

## **Bsc (Hons) Computing** Leeds Beckett University

09/2015 - 05/2018

Leeds, U.K, First Class Honors

Thesis

Image Classification using Convolutional Neural Network.

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

SUSE Cloud Native Scholarship Program (06/2021 - 08/2021)

Selected as a Scholarship Recipient for the SUSE Cloud Native Scholarship Program.

#### Employee of the Month (03/2021 - 03/2021)

Selected as Employee of the Month for the month of March for outstanding performance in the workplace.

## Academic Scholarship (09/2015 - 05/2018)

Academic Scholarship obtained via Academic Excellence throughout the course.